WENHU CHEN

Location: Santa Barbara, Phone: (805)455-1121, Email: wenhuchen@ucsb.edu Website: https://wenhuchen.github.io/, Github: https://github.com/wenhuchen

ABOUT ME

I'm an incoming tenure-track assistant professor at Computer Science of University of Waterloo. I obtained my Ph.D degree in Computer Science Department of University of California, Santa Barbara advised by William Wang and Xifeng Yan. I mainly work on natural language processing, deep learning and knowledge representation/reasoning. My research can be summarized as the following aspects:

- 1) natural language understanding: question answering, fact checking, dialog state tracking, etc.
- 2) natural language generation: data-to-text generation, dialog generation, visual captioning, etc.
- 3) **neural symbolic reasoning**: bridging the gap between neural and symbolic approaches.
- 4) few-shot/zero-shot learning: utilizing very few examples to generalize different NLP tasks.

EDUCATION

eBay Research

Location: Aachen, Germany

EDUCATION	
University of California, Santa Barbara Ph.D in Computer Science Advisor: William (Yang) Wang and Xifeng Yan	Sep 2017-Now
ETH Zurich, Switzerland Visiting in Computer Science Advisor: Aurelien Lucchi	June 2016-Dec 2016
RWTH Aachen University, Germany M.Sc. in Electronics Engineering	Sep 2014-Dec 2016
Huazhong University of Science and Technology, China B.Sc. in Electronics Engineering	Sep 2010-June 2014
RESEARCH EXPERIENCE	
Google Research Location: Pittsburgh, PA, USA Topic: Open Question Answering over tables and text Mentors: Ming-Wei Chang, Eva Schlinger, William Cohen	June 2020 - Dec 2020
Microsoft AI & Cloud Location: Seattle, WA, USA Topic: Visual Question Answering via compositional reasoning Mentors: Zhe Gan, Jingjing Liu	June 2019 - Sep 2019
Samsung Research America Location: Mountain View, CA, USA Topic: Deep learning model compression Mentors: Yi-Lin Shen, Hongxia Jin	June 2018 - Sep 2018
Microsoft Research Asia Location: Bejing, China Topic: Enhancing machine translation with data augmentation Mentors: Shujie Liu, Ming Zhou	Feb 2017 - Aug 2017

Dec 2015 - June 2016

Topic: Enhancing machine translation with statistical alignment

Mentors: Matusov Evgency, Shahram Khadivi

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Guest Lecturer, UCSB, 2018 Spring: CS 291K Advanced Deep Learning Teaching Assistant, UCSB, 2020 Spring: CS 165B Machine Learning

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

(Note: Most of the listed are 1st-tier AI conferences with acceptance rate between 20%-25%.)

[26] Zero-shot Fact Verification by Claim Generation

Liangming Pan, Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, Min-Yen Kan and William Wang

ACL 2021

[25] A Systematic Investigation of KB-Text Embedding Alignment at Scale

Vardaan Pahuja, Yu Gu, Wenhu Chen, Mehdi Bahrami, Lei Liu, Wei-Peng Chen and Yu Su

ACL 2021

[24] Unsupervised Multi-hop Question Answering by Question Generation

Liangming Pan, Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, Min-Yen Kan, William Yang Wang

NAACL 2021

[24] Unsupervised Multi-hop Question Answering by Question Generation

Liangming Pan, Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, Min-Yen Kan, William Yang Wang

NAACL 2021

[24] Unsupervised Multi-hop Question Answering by Question Generation

Liangming Pan, Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, Min-Yen Kan, William Yang Wang

NAACL 2021

[23] Open Question Answering over Tables and Text

Wenhu Chen, Ming-Wei Chang, Eva Schlinger, William Yang Wang, William W. Cohen

ICLR 2021

[22] KGPT: Knowledge-Grounded Pre-Training for Data-to-Text Generation

Wenhu Chen, Yu Su, Xifeng Yan, William Yang Wang.

EMNLP 2020

[21] HybridQA: A Dataset of Multi-Hop Question Answering over Tabular and Textual Data

Wenhu Chen, Hanwen Zha, Zhiyu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, Hong Wang, William Wang.

Findings of EMNLP 2020

[20] Logic2Text: High-Fidelity Natural Language Generation from Logical Forms

Zhiyu Chen, Wenhu Chen, Hanwen Zha, Xiyou Zhou, Yunkai Zhang, Sairam Sundaresan, William Yang Wang.

Findings of EMNLP 2020

[19] Meta Module Network for Compositional Visual Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, Zhe Gan, Linjie Li, Yu Cheng, William Wang, Jingjing Liu.

WACV 2021 (Best Student Paper Honorable Mention)

[18] Logical Natural Language Generation from Open-Domain Tables

Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Yu Su, Zhiyu Chen and William Yang Wang.

ACL 2020

[17] Few-shot NLG with Pre-trained Language Model

Zhiyu Chen, Harini Eavani, Wenhu Chen, Yinyin Liu and William Yang Wang.

ACL 2020

[16] VIOLIN: A Large-Scale Dataset for Video-and-Language Inference

Jingzhou Liu, Wenhu Chen, Yu Cheng, Zhe Gan, Licheng Yu, Yiming Yang, Jingjing Liu.

CVPR 2020

[15] TabFact: A Large-scale Dataset for Table-based Fact Verification

Wenhu Chen, Hongmin Wang, Jianshu Chen, Yunkai Zhang, Hong Wang, Shiyang Li, Xiyou Zhou and William Yang Wang.

ICLR 2020

[14] Generative Adversarial Zero-Shot Relational Learning for Knowledge Graphs

Pengda Qin, Xin Wang, Wenhu Chen, Chunyun Zhang, Weiran Xu, William Yang Wang.

AAAI 2020 (Oral)

[13] Enhancing the Locality and Breaking the Memory Bottleneck of Transformer on Time Series Forecasting Shiyang Li, Xiaoyong Jin, Yao Xuan, Xiyou Zhou, Wenhu Chen, Yu-Xiang Wang, Xifeng Yan.

NeurIPS 2019

[12] Interpreting and Improving Deep Neural SLU Models via Vocabulary Importance

Yilin Shen, Wenhu Chen, Hongxia Jin.

INTERSPEECH 2019 (Oral)

[11] Semantically Conditioned Dialog Response Generation via Hierarchical Disentangled Self-Attention Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Pengda Qin, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang.

ACL 2019

[10] Global Textual Relation Embedding for Relational Understanding

Zhiyu Chen, Hanwen Zha, Honglei Liu, Wenhu Chen, Xifeng Yan and Yu Su.

ACL 2019

[9] Mining Algorithm Roadmap in Scientific Publications

Hanwen Zha, Wenhu Chen, Keqian Li and Xifeng Yan.

KDD 2019 (Oral)

[8] How Large A Vocabulary Does Text Classification Need? A Variational Approach on Vocabulary Selection

Wenhu Chen, Yu Su, Yilin Shen, Zhiyu Chen, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang.

NAACL 2019 (Oral)

[7] XL-NBT: A Cross-lingual Neural Belief Tracking Framework

Wenhu Chen, Jianshu Chen, Yu Su, Xin Wang, Dong Yu, Xifeng Yan and William Yang Wang.

EMNLP 2018

[6] Triangular Architecture for Rare Language Translation

Shuo Ren, Wenhu Chen, Shujie Liu, Mu Li, Ming Zhou and Shuai Ma.

ACL 2018 (Oral)

[5] No Metrics Are Perfect: Adversarial Reward Learning for Visual Storytelling

Wenhu Chen*, Xin Wang*, Yuan-Fang Wang and William Yang Wang.

ACL 2018 (Oral)

[4] Variational Knowledge Graph Reasoning

Wenhu Chen, Wenhan Xiong, William Yang Wang, Xifeng Yan.

NAACL 2018 (Oral)

[3] Generative Bridging Network in Neural Sequence Prediction

Wenhu Chen, Guanlin Li, Shuo Ren, Shujie Liu, Zhirui Zhang, Mu Li, Ming Zhou.

NAACL 2018

[2] Video Captioning via Hierarchical Reinforcement Learning

Xin Wang, Wenhu Chen, Jiawei Wu, Yuan-fang Wang, William Yang Wang.

CVPR 2018

[1] Guided alignment training for topic-aware neural machine translation

Wenhu Chen, Evgeny Matusov, Shahram Khadivi, JT Peter.

AMTA 2016

[0] Using meta-information in neural machine translation

Evgeny Matusov, Wenhu Chen, Shahram Khadivi

US Patent 2017

SERVICE

2019: Program Committee in AAAI, NAACL, ICML, ACL, NeurIPS, TACL, EMNLP

2020: Program Committee in AAAI, ACL, ICML, EMNLP Session Chair, NeurIPS

2021: Program Committee in ICLR, NAACL, ACL, EMNLP Session Chair, NeurIPS

MENTORING

Rohan Bhatia (PhD student, UCSB)

Zhiyu Chen (PhD student, UCSB)

Xinyi Wang (PhD student, UCSB)

Yi-Lin Tuan (PhD student, UCSB)

Liangming Pan (PhD student, NUS)

ACADEMIC AWARD

2021 WACV Best Student Paper Honorable Mention.

2019 NERURIPS Outstanding Reviewer Award.

2018 Tencent AI Gift Award.

2016 IDEA Research Grant

2016 German National Scholarship

2014 China Scholarship Committee Scholarship

2012 MCM Finalist Award